Finding Aid for First Presbyterian Church (Pontiac, Mich.) records, 1824-1995
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
First Presbyterian Church (Pontiac, Mich.) records 1824-1995
First Presbyterian Church (Pontiac, Mich.).
15 oversize volumes
5.5 linear feet
86870 Ba 2; BA Outsize
Pontiac, Michigan Presbyterian church founded in 1824; session minutes, minutes of board of trustees, historical materials, church bulletins, and other church materials, including manuscript sermons and scrapbooks of minister William S. Jerome.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The record group was deposited by the church (donor no. 657 ).
No further additions to the records are expected.
The record group is open to research.
The First Presbyterian Church of Pontiac was established in 1824.
The record group is comprised of four series: Governance; Church Groups; History and Background; Church building; Financial; and Bulletins. Within Governance are found session minutes and minutes of the board of trustees. The Church Groups series includes minutes of the Men's Club, the Sunday School Workers organization, and the Society of United Workers, among other groups. The History and Background series includes a historical sketch of the church, as well as manuscript sermons and scrapbooks of minister William S. Jerome.
Subjects:
Jerome, William S.; Pontiac (Mich.); Presbyterian Church (U.S.A.)--Michigan--Pontiac.
Genre Terms:
Scrapbooks.; Sermons.
- Governance
  - Session minutes
    - February 1824-April 1867 (Box 1)
    - April 1867-April 1897 (Box 1)
      (including history of church to 1860, and articles of faith and form of covenant)
    - April 1897-March 1903 (Box 1)
    - March 1903-April 1904 (Box 1)
    - April 1904-October 1911 (Box 1)
    - October 1911-April 1920 (Box 1)
    - May 1920-March 1931 (Box 1)
    - 1930, 1931 [loose sheets] (Box 1)
  - Minutes of Board of Trustees
    - March 1869-March 1904 (Box 1)
    - 1904-1918 (Box 1)
  - Church register 1824-1906 (Box 1)
    (microfilm copy available)
- Church Groups
  - Minutes of Men's Club October 1928-October 1929 (Box 2)
  - Minutes of meetings of Sunday School workers 1925-1928 (Box 2)
  - Account book, Circle No. 1 1914-1924 (Box 2)
  - Constitution and by-laws of the United Workers and constitution and by-laws of the First Circle 1926-1927 (Box 2)
  - Record book of the Society of United Workers 1909-1922 (Box 2)
  - Pledge book and roll of Woman's Missionary Society 1920-1928 (Box 2)
- Historical and background
  - Scrapbooks of William S. Jerome, 3 volumes (Box 2)
  - Manuscript sermons of William S. Jerome (Box 2)
  - Constitution and by-laws (Box 2)
  - "A Brief History of the Presbyterian Church of Pontiac to 1860" (Box 2)
  - Historical miscellanea (including deed to land 1833) (Box 2)
  - Papers re. 150th Anniversary of church 1974 (Box 2)
  - Papers re. Michigan Council of Religious Education and International Council of Religious Education, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Enrollment cards: Pontiac Community Training School for Church School Leaders (Box 2)
  - Miscellanea; include reports, resolutions, correspondence, etc. (Box 2)
- Church building
  - Building Committee minutes 1917-1918 (Box 3)
  - Contracts for church building 1918-1924 (Box 3)
  - Contracts for church building 1924 (Box 3)
  - Bills and statements re. church building 1923-1925 (Box 3)
  - Cancelled checks and stubs re. church building 1923-1925 (Box 3)
  - Receipts of building fund 1918-1920, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Receipts, accounts, pledges of building fund 1915-1925, 3 folders (Box 3)
  - Correspondence with companies interested in church buildings 1914-1917, 5 folders (Box 3)
- Financial
  - Miscellaneous treasurer's reports 1915-1920 (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous reports 1924-1935 (Box 3)
  - Quarterly statement and receipt books of member's giving, 5 volumes (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous financial journals and ledgers, 6 volumes (Box 3)
  - Treasurer's record book 1916-1924 (Volume 1)
  - Ledgers with contributions of members, 14 volumes
    - Ledgers with contributions of members (Volume 2)
    - Ledgers with contributions of members (Volume 3)
      (continued)
    - Ledgers with contributions of members (Volume 4)
    - Ledgers with contributions of members (Volume 5)
    - Ledgers with contributions of members (Volume 6)
    - Ledgers with contributions of members (Volume 7)
    - Ledgers with contributions of members (Volume 8)
    - Ledgers with contributions of members (Volume 9)
    - Ledgers with contributions of members (Volume 10)
    - Ledgers with contributions of members (Volume 11)
    - Ledgers with contributions of members (Volume 12)
    - Ledgers with contributions of members (Volume 13)
    - Ledgers with contributions of members (Volume 14)
    - Ledgers with contributions of members (Volume 15)
- Bulletins
  - 1937-1962 (Box 4)
  - 1963-1986 (Box 5)
  - 1987-1995 (Box 6)